C-605,Sukh Sagar Building , Santacruz East Mumbai City

Pin Code: 400055

Software Developer

Adnan Shaikh



Mobile : 8655868744

Email: adnanshaikh53@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am a Software Developer with around 4 years of Experience in Software Development specialised in Java, AI/ML from Mumbai who loves to write Software to build great Products and help businesses succeed with their goals

I have been working professionally in Software Development since 2015 across the Web space with experience in Payments domain

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (2011-15)

University of Mumbai 3 GPA

HSC Maharashtra Board(2009-11)

M H S S Jr College 3.4 GPA

SSC Maharashtra Board (March 2009)

Guru Nanak High School 3.56 GPA

ACTIVITIES

I have worked on gizmotechno.com, a smart home innovation company based in Maharashtra, India and helped them develop their website in Django, Python

I also work with MESCO, an NGO based in Mumbai working for the welfare of poor students and families by offering assistance in Healthcare, Education and other schemes.

I am an active food blogger exploring various places in Mumbai/Pune in search of good food and updating my reviews on zomato @adnanshaikh53

WORK EXPERIENCE: 4.2 years

Software Engineer Global PayPlus(February 2018-Present): Finastra, Pune

- Development of New Requirements in High Value, Mass Pay and Instant Payments in GPP Product.
- Worked on new requirements of Product for Citibank, CitiBanamex and State Street Bank, also handled various Customer defects for these banks

Systems Engineer (September 2015- January 2018) Tata Consultancy Services, Mumbai

- Development and Use Case wise performance Improvement for Inventory Management and Production Modules of <u>iON ERP</u> Solution.
- Developed a new product <u>iON ERP Lite</u>, a minified and compact version of the existing solution

TECHNOLOGIES

Server side: Python ,Java, **Client side:** Javascript, jQuery **Database:** Oracle SQL, MySQL

Frameworks: Worked with Spring/Hibernate in Java, Python-

Django webframework

Others: Elasticsearch, IBM MQ

Development Tools: Pycharm, MyEclipse, SQL Developer,

SVN/ Git

Certifications: Machine Learning, Programming Fundamentals:

Data Structures, from LinkedIn.

Ongoing Courses: Currently pursuing a course in Data Science

from DataCamp.com

PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: 13 October, 1993

Nationality: Indian

Mobile: 08655868744

Email: adnanshaikh53@gmail.com